<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Real-Time on Scott Obert</title><link>https://scottobert.com/tags/real-time/</link><description>Recent content in Real-Time on Scott Obert</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;2022 Scott Obert</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottobert.com/tags/real-time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real-time Data Synchronization: Using DynamoDB Streams and Lambda to Keep OpenSearch Indexes Current</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/dynamodb-streams-opensearch-sync/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/dynamodb-streams-opensearch-sync/</guid><description>&lt;p>Building modern applications often requires the ability to perform full-text searches with fuzzy matching capabilities on data that&amp;rsquo;s primarily stored in NoSQL databases like DynamoDB. While DynamoDB excels at fast key-based lookups and can handle massive scale, it lacks the sophisticated search capabilities that applications need for features like autocomplete, typo-tolerant search, and complex text analysis. OpenSearch (the open-source fork of Elasticsearch) provides these advanced search capabilities, but keeping it synchronized with your primary data store presents unique challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real-time Processing Architectures</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/real-time-processing-architectures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/real-time-processing-architectures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Real-time processing architectures address the fundamental challenge of extracting actionable insights from continuously flowing data streams while maintaining low latency and high throughput requirements. Unlike batch processing systems that operate on static datasets with relaxed timing constraints, real-time systems must process events as they arrive, often within milliseconds or seconds of generation. This temporal sensitivity introduces unique design considerations around event ordering, backpressure handling, and state management that distinguish real-time architectures from their batch-oriented counterparts.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>