<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Serverless on Scott Obert</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/tags/serverless/</link><description>Recent content in Serverless on Scott Obert</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;2022 Scott Obert</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottobert.github.io/tags/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cost Optimization Strategies for AWS Serverless Applications</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-serverless-cost-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-serverless-cost-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While serverless architectures can significantly reduce operational costs, they require thoughtful design and configuration to maximize cost efficiency. This guide explores practical strategies for optimizing costs in AWS serverless applications, based on real-world experience and proven patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lambda-function-optimization">Lambda Function Optimization&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="memory-and-duration-trade-offs">Memory and Duration Trade-offs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The relationship between Lambda memory allocation and execution duration isn&amp;rsquo;t always intuitive. Higher memory allocations often lead to faster execution times, potentially reducing overall costs. When right-sizing memory for your functions, start with the minimum required memory of 128MB and gradually increase while monitoring performance. In many cases, doubling the memory from 128MB to 256MB can cut execution time in half, resulting in lower overall costs despite the higher memory price.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Event-Driven Architectures with AWS SNS/SQS and TypeScript</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-sns-sqs-typescript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-sns-sqs-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Event-driven architectures are fundamental to building scalable, loosely coupled systems in the cloud. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to use AWS SNS (Simple Notification Service) and SQS (Simple Queue Service) with TypeScript to create robust event-driven applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-event-driven-architecture">Why Event-Driven Architecture?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Event-driven architectures bring numerous advantages to modern cloud applications. At their core, they enable loose coupling between services, allowing components to evolve independently without affecting the entire system. This architectural approach naturally leads to improved scalability and resilience, as services can scale independently based on their specific load patterns. When traffic spikes occur, the system can better handle the increased load by buffering messages and processing them at an appropriate pace. The architecture also simplifies error handling and retry logic through built-in messaging capabilities, while the overall system becomes more maintainable due to clear boundaries between components.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Securing AWS Lambda Functions: Best Practices and Implementation Guide</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/securing-aws-lambda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/securing-aws-lambda/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following our exploration of AWS Lambda with TypeScript and Step Functions, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand how to properly secure your serverless applications. Security in serverless architectures requires a different approach from traditional applications, as the infrastructure is managed by AWS while you maintain responsibility for securing your application logic and data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="understanding-the-shared-responsibility-model">Understanding the Shared Responsibility Model&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the AWS Lambda context, the shared responsibility model takes on a unique form. AWS handles the security of the runtime environment, execution environment isolation, and underlying infrastructure. However, developers are responsible for securing their application code, managing IAM permissions, protecting sensitive data, and ensuring secure communication between services. This division of responsibility allows you to focus on application-specific security while AWS handles the infrastructure security.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Step Functions: Orchestrating AWS Lambda Workflows in TypeScript</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-step-functions-typescript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-step-functions-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Building on our previous exploration of AWS Lambda with TypeScript, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into how Step Functions can orchestrate complex workflows across multiple Lambda functions. Step Functions provide a reliable way to coordinate distributed components and handle long-running processes in your serverless applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-step-functions">Why Step Functions?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While individual Lambda functions excel at discrete tasks, real-world applications demand more sophisticated orchestration capabilities. Applications typically need to manage complex workflows with multiple interconnected steps, implement comprehensive error handling and retry logic, and handle processes that extend beyond Lambda&amp;rsquo;s 15-minute execution limit. Additionally, maintaining state between steps and coordinating parallel task execution are common requirements in distributed systems. Step Functions address these challenges by providing a robust state machine-based orchestration service that brings structure and reliability to complex serverless workflows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to deploy an AWS Lambda function written in TypeScript using SAM CLI</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-lambda-typescript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 13:30:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-lambda-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the world of AWS Serverless! In this blog post, we will be discussing how to deploy an AWS Lambda function written in TypeScript using the AWS SAM CLI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWS Lambda is a compute service that allows you to run your code in response to events or triggers, such as changes to data in an S3 bucket, or updates to a DynamoDB table. AWS Serverless Application Model (SAM) is an open-source framework for building serverless applications. The SAM CLI provides a local development and testing environment for AWS Serverless applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Database Design for Serverless Applications: NoSQL Patterns and Data Modeling</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/database-design-serverless-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/database-design-serverless-applications/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In our Modern Development Practices series, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered test-driven development, code quality gates, API design patterns, and microservices communication. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into database design for serverless applications – a critical aspect that can make or break your application&amp;rsquo;s performance, scalability, and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serverless applications demand a different approach to data storage. Traditional relational database patterns often don&amp;rsquo;t align with the ephemeral, stateless nature of serverless functions. Instead, we need to embrace NoSQL patterns, denormalization strategies, and event-driven data synchronization.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>