<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DynamoDB on Scott Obert</title><link>https://scottobert.com/tags/dynamodb/</link><description>Recent content in DynamoDB on Scott Obert</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;2022 Scott Obert</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottobert.com/tags/dynamodb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real-time Data Synchronization: Using DynamoDB Streams and Lambda to Keep OpenSearch Indexes Current</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/dynamodb-streams-opensearch-sync/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/dynamodb-streams-opensearch-sync/</guid><description>&lt;p>Building modern applications often requires the ability to perform full-text searches with fuzzy matching capabilities on data that&amp;rsquo;s primarily stored in NoSQL databases like DynamoDB. While DynamoDB excels at fast key-based lookups and can handle massive scale, it lacks the sophisticated search capabilities that applications need for features like autocomplete, typo-tolerant search, and complex text analysis. OpenSearch (the open-source fork of Elasticsearch) provides these advanced search capabilities, but keeping it synchronized with your primary data store presents unique challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Database Design for Serverless Applications: NoSQL Patterns and Data Modeling</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/database-design-serverless-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/database-design-serverless-applications/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In our Modern Development Practices series, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered test-driven development, code quality gates, API design patterns, and microservices communication. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into database design for serverless applications – a critical aspect that can make or break your application&amp;rsquo;s performance, scalability, and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Serverless applications demand a different approach to data storage. Traditional relational database patterns often don&amp;rsquo;t align with the ephemeral, stateless nature of serverless functions. Instead, we need to embrace NoSQL patterns, denormalization strategies, and event-driven data synchronization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CQRS Implementation with AWS Services</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/cqrs-implementation-aws-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/cqrs-implementation-aws-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>Command Query Responsibility Segregation represents a fundamental shift in how we think about data persistence and retrieval in distributed systems. Rather than treating reads and writes as symmetric operations against a single data model, CQRS acknowledges the inherent differences between these operations and optimizes each path independently. In the context of AWS services, this pattern becomes particularly powerful when we leverage the managed services ecosystem to handle the complexity of maintaining separate command and query models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Event Sourcing Patterns in AWS</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/event-sourcing-patterns-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/event-sourcing-patterns-aws/</guid><description>&lt;p>Event sourcing fundamentally changes how applications handle state management by storing every state change as an immutable event rather than maintaining current state snapshots. This architectural pattern becomes particularly powerful when implemented on AWS, where managed services provide the scalability and durability required for enterprise-grade event sourcing systems. Understanding how to leverage AWS services effectively for event sourcing can transform application architectures from brittle state-dependent systems into resilient, audit-friendly, and highly scalable solutions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>