<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Scott Obert</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Scott Obert</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;2022 Scott Obert</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottobert.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Harnessing AI in Software Engineering: Opportunities and Challenges</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/using-ai-in-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/using-ai-in-software-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) is rapidly reshaping the landscape of software engineering. From automating repetitive tasks to enhancing code quality and enabling smarter decision-making, AI-powered tools are becoming essential in the modern developer’s toolkit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="key-applications-of-ai-in-software-engineering">Key Applications of AI in Software Engineering&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-code-generation-and-completion">1. Code Generation and Completion&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>AI-powered code assistants, such as GitHub Copilot, can suggest code snippets, complete functions, and even generate entire modules based on natural language prompts. This accelerates development and reduces boilerplate coding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to deploy an AWS Lambda function written in TypeScript using SAM CLI</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-lambda-typescript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 13:30:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/aws-lambda-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the world of AWS Serverless! In this blog post, we will be discussing how to deploy an AWS Lambda function written in TypeScript using the AWS SAM CLI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWS Lambda is a compute service that allows you to run your code in response to events or triggers, such as changes to data in an S3 bucket, or updates to a DynamoDB table. AWS Serverless Application Model (SAM) is an open-source framework for building serverless applications. The SAM CLI provides a local development and testing environment for AWS Serverless applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>git reset to a given commit</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/git-reset-to-commit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 09:50:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/git-reset-to-commit/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="safely-resetting-to-a-previous-commit-in-git">Safely Resetting to a Previous Commit in Git&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When working with Git, sometimes you need to reset your working tree to a specific commit while preserving the commit history. This guide explains how to do this safely and understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening behind the scenes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-problem">The Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Typically, when developers want to revert to an older commit, they might reach for &lt;code>git reset --hard&lt;/code>. However, this can be dangerous as it:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decompiling dotnet apps</title><link>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/decompiling-dotnet-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 15:09:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.github.io/posts/decompiling-dotnet-apps/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes as developers we run into a legacy application that has been running in production for years when suddenly a bug surfaces. If nobody knows where the source code for that legacy application is, that can be a huge problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-net-decompilation">Introduction to .NET Decompilation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Decompilation is the process of converting compiled .NET assemblies (DLLs or EXEs) back into readable source code. This can be incredibly useful when:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dealing with legacy applications without source code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debugging production issues where deployed code differs from source control&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understanding third-party libraries when documentation is insufficient&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Investigating potential security issues or malware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="using-dotpeek">Using dotPeek&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/decompiler/">dotPeek&lt;/a> by JetBrains is a powerful free .NET decompiler that can help solve these problems. I recently had an occasion to use it, and even without the .pdb file, it was able to decompile the code to be very close to the source code we had in source control that we knew wasn&amp;rsquo;t what was running in production.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>