<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development on Scott Obert</title><link>https://scottobert.com/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on Scott Obert</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy;2022 Scott Obert</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scottobert.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reverting Git Commits Safely: Undoing Changes Without Losing History</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/reverting-git-commits-safely/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/reverting-git-commits-safely/</guid><description>&lt;p>When working on complex projects, you&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably encounter situations where you need to undo changes from a specific commit that&amp;rsquo;s buried several commits back in your history. Recently, I faced this exact scenario when commit &lt;code>1d814e5&lt;/code> needed to be reverted from our development branch, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the most recent commit. This post explores the safest and most effective ways to handle this situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-challenge">The Challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Looking at a typical git reflog, you might see something like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Event-Driven Architectures with AWS SNS/SQS and TypeScript</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/aws-sns-sqs-typescript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/aws-sns-sqs-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Event-driven architectures are fundamental to building scalable, loosely coupled systems in the cloud. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to use AWS SNS (Simple Notification Service) and SQS (Simple Queue Service) with TypeScript to create robust event-driven applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-event-driven-architecture">Why Event-Driven Architecture?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Event-driven architectures bring numerous advantages to modern cloud applications. At their core, they enable loose coupling between services, allowing components to evolve independently without affecting the entire system. This architectural approach naturally leads to improved scalability and resilience, as services can scale independently based on their specific load patterns. When traffic spikes occur, the system can better handle the increased load by buffering messages and processing them at an appropriate pace. The architecture also simplifies error handling and retry logic through built-in messaging capabilities, while the overall system becomes more maintainable due to clear boundaries between components.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Securing AWS Lambda Functions: Best Practices and Implementation Guide</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/securing-aws-lambda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/securing-aws-lambda/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following our exploration of AWS Lambda with TypeScript and Step Functions, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand how to properly secure your serverless applications. Security in serverless architectures requires a different approach from traditional applications, as the infrastructure is managed by AWS while you maintain responsibility for securing your application logic and data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="understanding-the-shared-responsibility-model">Understanding the Shared Responsibility Model&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the AWS Lambda context, the shared responsibility model takes on a unique form. AWS handles the security of the runtime environment, execution environment isolation, and underlying infrastructure. However, developers are responsible for securing their application code, managing IAM permissions, protecting sensitive data, and ensuring secure communication between services. This division of responsibility allows you to focus on application-specific security while AWS handles the infrastructure security.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Step Functions: Orchestrating AWS Lambda Workflows in TypeScript</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/aws-step-functions-typescript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/aws-step-functions-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Building on our previous exploration of AWS Lambda with TypeScript, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into how Step Functions can orchestrate complex workflows across multiple Lambda functions. Step Functions provide a reliable way to coordinate distributed components and handle long-running processes in your serverless applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-step-functions">Why Step Functions?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While individual Lambda functions excel at discrete tasks, real-world applications demand more sophisticated orchestration capabilities. Applications typically need to manage complex workflows with multiple interconnected steps, implement comprehensive error handling and retry logic, and handle processes that extend beyond Lambda&amp;rsquo;s 15-minute execution limit. Additionally, maintaining state between steps and coordinating parallel task execution are common requirements in distributed systems. Step Functions address these challenges by providing a robust state machine-based orchestration service that brings structure and reliability to complex serverless workflows.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to deploy an AWS Lambda function written in TypeScript using SAM CLI</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/aws-lambda-typescript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 13:30:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/aws-lambda-typescript/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the world of AWS Serverless! In this blog post, we will be discussing how to deploy an AWS Lambda function written in TypeScript using the AWS SAM CLI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AWS Lambda is a compute service that allows you to run your code in response to events or triggers, such as changes to data in an S3 bucket, or updates to a DynamoDB table. AWS Serverless Application Model (SAM) is an open-source framework for building serverless applications. The SAM CLI provides a local development and testing environment for AWS Serverless applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>git reset to a given commit</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/git-reset-to-commit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 09:50:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/git-reset-to-commit/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="safely-resetting-to-a-previous-commit-in-git">Safely Resetting to a Previous Commit in Git&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When working with Git, sometimes you need to reset your working tree to a specific commit while preserving the commit history. This guide explains how to do this safely and understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening behind the scenes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-problem">The Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Typically, when developers want to revert to an older commit, they might reach for &lt;code>git reset --hard&lt;/code>. However, this can be dangerous as it:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decompiling dotnet apps</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/decompiling-dotnet-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 15:09:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/decompiling-dotnet-apps/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes as developers we run into a legacy application that has been running in production for years when suddenly a bug surfaces. If nobody knows where the source code for that legacy application is, that can be a huge problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-net-decompilation">Introduction to .NET Decompilation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Decompilation is the process of converting compiled .NET assemblies (DLLs or EXEs) back into readable source code. This can be incredibly useful when:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Dealing with legacy applications without source code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debugging production issues where deployed code differs from source control&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Understanding third-party libraries when documentation is insufficient&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Investigating potential security issues or malware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="using-dotpeek">Using dotPeek&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/decompiler/">dotPeek&lt;/a> by JetBrains is a powerful free .NET decompiler that can help solve these problems. I recently had an occasion to use it, and even without the .pdb file, it was able to decompile the code to be very close to the source code we had in source control that we knew wasn&amp;rsquo;t what was running in production.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code Quality Gates: Automated Standards Enforcement</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/code-quality-gates-automated-standards-enforcement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/code-quality-gates-automated-standards-enforcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code quality gates serve as automated checkpoints that prevent substandard code from progressing through your development pipeline. When implemented effectively, they maintain consistent standards across teams while accelerating development by catching issues early and reducing manual review overhead.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="understanding-quality-gates">Understanding Quality Gates&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Quality gates are automated checks that evaluate code against predefined criteria before allowing it to proceed to the next stage of development. Unlike simple linting, quality gates encompass comprehensive analysis including code coverage, complexity metrics, security vulnerabilities, and architectural compliance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Test-Driven Development in TypeScript: Beyond the Basics</title><link>https://scottobert.com/posts/test-driven-development-typescript-beyond-basics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://scottobert.com/posts/test-driven-development-typescript-beyond-basics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Test-Driven Development (TDD) has evolved significantly with modern TypeScript tooling and frameworks. While most developers understand the basic red-green-refactor cycle, mastering TDD in TypeScript requires understanding advanced patterns, effective mocking strategies, and leveraging the type system for better test design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="beyond-basic-tdd-advanced-patterns">Beyond Basic TDD: Advanced Patterns&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="type-driven-test-design">Type-Driven Test Design&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>TypeScript&amp;rsquo;s type system provides unique opportunities to improve test design. Instead of just testing implementation details, we can use types to guide our test structure and ensure comprehensive coverage:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>